{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Direct costs component of the fixed capital consists of", "opta": "contingencies", "optb": "onsite and offsite costs", "optc": "labour costs", "optd": "raw material costs", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Out of the following, the depreciation calculated by the __________ method is the maximum.", "opta": "diminishing balance", "optb": "straight line", "optc": "sum of the years digit", "optd": "sinking fund", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio of working capital to total capital investment for most chemical plants (except for non-seasonal based products) is in the range of __________ percent.", "opta": "0.1 to 1", "optb": "1 to 2", "optc": "10 to 20", "optd": "50 to 60", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Utilities cost in the operation of chemical process plant comes under the", "opta": "plant overhead cost", "optb": "fixed charges", "optc": "direct production cost", "optd": "general expenses", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick out the wrong statement.", "opta": "The annual depreciation rate for machinery and equipments in a chemical process plant is about 10% of the fixed capital investment.", "optb": "Annual depreciation rate of buildings in a chemical plant is about 3% of its initial cost.", "optc": "Insurance rates on annual basis in a chemical plant may be about 1% of the fixed capital investment.", "optd": "In a chemical industry, research and development cost amounts to about 15% of net sales realisation (NSR).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ method for profitability evaluation of a project does not account for investment cost due to land.", "opta": "Net present worth", "optb": "Pay out period", "optc": "Discounted cash flow", "optd": "Rate of return on investment", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total investment in a project is Rs. 10 lakhs and the annual profit is 1.5 lakhs. If the project life is 10 years, then the simple rate of return on investment is", "opta": "15%", "optb": "10%", "optc": "1.5%", "optd": "150%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nominal and effective interest rates are equal, when the interest is compounded", "opta": "quarterly", "optb": "semi-annually", "optc": "annually", "optd": "in no case, they are equal", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following elements is not included in the scope of market analysis ?", "opta": "Competition from other manufactures.", "optb": "Product distribution.", "optc": "Opportunities", "optd": "Economics", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ of depreciation calculation accounts for the interest on investement.", "opta": "Straight line method", "optb": "Declining balance", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "neither (a) nor (b).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a component of working capital ?", "opta": "Raw materials is stock.", "optb": "Finished products in stock.", "optc": "Transportation facilities.", "optd": "Semi-finished products in the process.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In declining balance method of depreciation calculation, the", "opta": "value of the asset decreases linearly with time.", "optb": "annual cost of depreciation is same every year.", "optc": "annual depreciation is the fixed percentage of the property value at the beginning of the particular year.", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following relationship is not correct is case of a chemical process plant ?", "opta": "Manufacturing cost = direct product cost + fixed charges + plant overhead costs", "optb": "General expenses = administrative expenses + distribution & marketing expenses", "optc": "Total product cost = manufacturing cost + general expenses", "optd": "Total product cost = direct production cost + plant overhead cost.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a given fluid, as the pipe diameter increases, the pumping cost", "opta": "decreases.", "optb": "increases.", "optc": "remains the same.", "optd": "may increase or decrease, depending upon whether the fluid is Newtonian or non-Newtonian.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which of the electric power generation system, the operating cost is minimum ?", "opta": "Thermal", "optb": "Nuclear", "optc": "Hydroelectric", "optd": "Fast breeder reactor", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Accumulated sum at the end of 5 years, if Rs. 10000 is invested now at 10% interest per annum on a compound basis is Rs.", "opta": "15000", "optb": "16105", "optc": "18105", "optd": "12500", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Operating profit of a chemical plant is equal to", "opta": "profit before interest and tax i.e., net profit + interest + tax", "optb": "profit after tax plus depreciation", "optc": "net profit + tax", "optd": "profit after tax", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a manufacturing industry, break even point occurs, when the", "opta": "total annual rate of production equals the assigned value.", "optb": "total annual product cost equals the total annual sales.", "optc": "annual profit equals the expected value.", "optd": "annual sales equals the fixed cost.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gross earning is equal to the total income minus", "opta": "total product cost", "optb": "fixed cost", "optc": "income tax", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The depreciation during the year 'n', in diminishing balance method of depreciation calculation, is calculated by multiplying a fixed percentage 'N' to the", "opta": "initial cost.", "optb": "book value at the end of (n - 1)th year,", "optc": "depreciation during the (n - 1)th year.", "optd": "difference between initial cost and salvage value.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Scheduling provides information about the", "opta": "proper utilisation of machines.", "optb": "means to minimise idle time for machines.", "optc": "time of completion of job.", "optd": "time of starting of job and also about how much work should be completed during a particular period.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The inventory of raw materials included in the working capital is usually about __________ months supply of raw materials valued at delivery prices.", "opta": "one", "optb": "three", "optc": "six", "optd": "twelve", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the costliest material of construction used in pressure vessel construction ?", "opta": "Low alloy steel", "optb": "Lead", "optc": "Titanium", "optd": "High alloy steel", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most chemical plants use an initial working capital amounting to 10-20% of the total capital investment. But this percentage may increase to __________ percent in case of seasonal products manufacturing plant.", "opta": "30", "optb": "50", "optc": "75", "optd": "95", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fixed charges for a chemical plant does not include the", "opta": "interest on borrowed money.", "optb": "rent of land and buildings.", "optc": "property tax, insurance and depreciation.", "optd": "repair and maintenance charges.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "'Utilities' in a chemical process plant includes compressed air, steam, water, electrical power, oxygen, acetylene, fuel gases etc. Utility costs for ordinary chemical process plants ranges roughly from __________ percent of the total product cost.", "opta": "l to 5", "optb": "10 to 20", "optc": "25 to 35", "optd": "35 to 45", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The economic life of a large chemical process plant as compared to a small chemical plant is", "opta": "only slightly more", "optb": "much more", "optc": "slightly less", "optd": "almost equal", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cost of instrumentation in a modern chemical plant ranges from __________ percent of the total plant cost.", "opta": "5 to 10", "optb": "20 to 30", "optc": "40 to 50", "optd": "60 to 70", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ taxes are based on gross earnings.", "opta": "Property", "optb": "Excise", "optc": "Income", "optd": "Capital gain", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick out the wrong statement.", "opta": "Net worth means paid up share capital and reserve & surplus (i.e. shareholders equity).", "optb": "Return on equity = profit after tax/net worth.", "optc": "Working capital turn over ratio = sales/net working capital.", "optd": "Total cost of production is more than net sales realisation (NSR) at break even point.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the interest rate of 10% per period is compounded half yearly, the actual annual return on the principal will be __________ percent.", "opta": "10", "optb": "20", "optc": ">20", "optd": "< 20", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a component of working capital investment ?", "opta": "Utilities plants.", "optb": "Maintenance and repair inventory.", "optc": "Process equipments.", "optd": "Depreciation.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "'Six-tenth factor' rule is used for estimating the", "opta": "equipment installation cost.", "optb": "equipment cost by scaling.", "optc": "cost of piping.", "optd": "utilities cost.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Payback period", "opta": "and economic life of a project are the same.", "optb": "is the length of time over which the earnings on a project equals the investment.", "optc": "is affected by the variation in earnings after the recovery of the investment.", "optd": "all (a), (b) and (c).", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an ordinary chemical plant, electrical installation cost may be about", "opta": "10-15% of purchased equipment cost.", "optb": "3-10% of fixed capital investment.", "optc": "either (a) or (b).", "optd": "neither (a) nor (b).", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick out the wrong statement.", "opta": "Debt-equity ratio of a chemical company describes the lenders contribution for each rupee of owner's contribution i.e., debt-equity ratio = total debt/net worth.", "optb": "Return on investment (ROI) is the ratio of profit before interest & tax and capital employed (i.e. net worth + total debt).", "optc": "Working capital = current assets + current liability.", "optd": "Turn over = opening stock + production closing stock.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Personnel working in the market research group is reponsible for the job of", "opta": "equipment selection.", "optb": "product evaluation.", "optc": "equipment design.", "optd": "cost estimation.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\"Break-even point\" is the point of intersection of", "opta": "fixed cost and total cost.", "optb": "total cost and sales revenue.", "optc": "fixed cost and sales revenue.", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "'P' is the investment made on an equipment, 'S' is its salvage value and 'n is the life of the equipment in years. The depreciation for rath year by the sum-of years digit method will be", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick out the wrong statement.", "opta": "Gross revenue is that total amount of capital received as a result of the sale of goods or service.", "optb": "Net revenue is the total profit remaining after deducting all costs excluding taxes.", "optc": "The ratio of immediately available cash to the total current liabilities is known as the cash ratio.", "optd": "Consolidated income statement based on a given time period indicates surplus capital and shows the relationship among total income, costs & profit over the time interval.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The payback method for the measurement of return on investment", "opta": "gives a correct picture of profitability.", "optb": "underemphasises liquidity.", "optc": "does not measure the discounted rate of return.", "optd": "takes into account the cash inflows after the recovery of investments.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Annual depreciation costs are constant, when the __________ method of depreciation calculation is used.", "opta": "declining balance", "optb": "straight line", "optc": "sum of the years digit", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cost incurred towards __________ in a chemical plant is a component of the utilities cost.", "opta": "water supply", "optb": "running a control laboratory", "optc": "property protection", "optd": "medical services", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Equipment installation cost in a chemical process plant ranges from __________ percent of the purchased equipment cost.", "opta": "10 to 20", "optb": "35 to 45", "optc": "55 to 65", "optd": "70 to 80", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Annual depreciation cost are not constant when, the __________ method of depreciation calculation is used.", "opta": "straight line", "optb": "sinking fund", "optc": "present worth", "optd": "declining balance.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick out the wrong statement.", "opta": "Longer tubes are less expensive per unit heat transfer area as compared to shorter tubes.", "optb": "A cost index is merely a number for a given year showing the cost at that time relative to a certain base year.", "optc": "Turn over ratio of a chemical plant is the ratio of gross annual sales to the fixed capital investment.", "optd": "Plates with butt welded joints are less expensive compared to lap welded joints, because squaring of plates is not necessary.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Construction expenses are roughly __________ percent of the total direct cost of the plant.", "opta": "2", "optb": "10", "optc": "30", "optd": "50", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A machine has an initial value of Rs. 5000, service life of 5 years and final salvage value of Rs. 1000. The annual depreciation cost by straight line method is Rs.", "opta": "300", "optb": "600", "optc": "800", "optd": "1000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a component of depreciation cost ?", "opta": "Repairs and maintenance cost.", "optb": "Loss due to obsolescence of the equipment.", "optc": "Loss due to decrease in the demand of product.", "optd": "Loss due to accident/breakdown in the machinery.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A series of equal payments (e.g., deposit or cost) made at equal intervals of time is known as", "opta": "perpetuity", "optb": "capital charge factor", "optc": "annuity", "optd": "future worth", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}